ShanghaiTech University, 393 Middle Huaxia Road, Pudong, Shanghai, 201210

🛮 +86 18521734236 | 💌 liuzhj2022@shanghaitech.edu.cn | 😭 rroscha.github.io | 🖸 github.com/Rroscha

Personal Profile

Energetic, creative, and responsible student, currently studying at ShanghaiTech University in a graduate program. Passionate about software engineering, having two or more years of expertise, and specializing in program analysis, malware detection, fuzzing, LLMs, and so on.

Education

ShanghaiTech University

Pudong, Shanghai

Master of Science in Computer Science, GPA: 3.89/4.0

September 2022 - Current

• Courses: Program Analysis, Algorithm Design, Machine Learning, Cybersecurity

Chang'an University

Xi'an, Shaanxi

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science, GPA: 4.20/5.0 (ranking 1th)

August 2018 - July 2022

· Courses: Compiler, Networking, Operating System, Database, Computer Architecture

Publications

CONFERENCE PROCEEDINGS

Enhancing Malware Detection for Android Apps: Detecting Fine-granularity Malicious Components Zhijie Liu, Liangfeng Zhang, Yutian Tang*

2023 38th IEEE/ACM International Conference on Automated Software Engineering (ASE), 2023

PREPRINT ARTICLES

No Need to Lift a Finger Anymore? Assessing the Quality of Code Generation by ChatGPT Zhijie Liu, Yutian Tang*, Xiapu Luo, Zhou Yuming, Liangfeng Zhang arXiv preprint arXiv:2307.00588 (2023). 2023

ChatGPT vs SBST: A Comparative Assessment of Unit Test Suite Generation Yutian Tang*, Zhijie Liu, Zhichao Zhou, Xiapu Luo

arXiv preprint arXiv:2307.00588 (2023). 2023

Experience

ShanghaiTech University, CATLab

Pudong, Shanghai

Project: Android Malicious Component Detection

January 2022 - Current

- Summarized the shortcomings of existing Android malware detection systems.
- · Designed a new approach based on deep learning and genetic algorithm for detecting Android malicious components adaptively.
- Improved the performance and robustness of Android malware detection by up to 10% and 20%, respectively.
- Supported fine-granularity Android malicious component detection.

Tencent Keen Lab Xuhui, Shanghai Proiect: ... August 2023 - Current

• ...

Skills

Programming C/C++ (Windows and Linux), Java, Python (PyTorch, NumPy, Scikit-learn, etc.), Assembly, Structured Query Language, Cypher.

Miscellaneous Windows, Linux, Bash Shell, JetBrains, ETFX(Overleaf), Microsoft Office, Git, IDA Pro, Matlab.

Services

2024 Program Committee, International Conference on Software Engineering & Knowledge Engineering (SEKE) USA

Program Committee, International Conference on Software Engineering & Knowledge Engineering (SEKE)

USA

Awards

2022	Outstanding Thesis Award, Undergraduate Research Scholars, Chang'an University	China
2022	Outstanding Graduate Award, Undergraduate Scholarships, Chang'an University	China
2022	The Second Class Prize Winner, ASC22 Student Supercomputer Challenge	China
2021	National Scholarship, Undergraduate Scholarships, Chang'an University	China
2021	Meritorious Winner, 2021 Interdisciplinary Contest in Modeling	USA
2020	National Scholarship, Undergraduate Scholarships, Chang'an University	China
2019	Second Prize of Zhaoshang-Road Scholarship, Undergraduate Scholarships, Chang'an University	China